<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>chat.simplex.simplex</id>
  
  <name>SimpleX Chat</name>
  <summary>SimpleX - a private &amp; encrypted open-source messenger without any user IDs (not even random ones)!</summary>

  <developer id="chat.simplex">
    <name>SimpleX Chat</name>
  </developer>
  
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  
  <description>
    <p>SimpleX - the first messaging platform that has no user identifiers, not even random numbers!</p>
    <p>Security assessment was done by Trail of Bits in November 2022.</p>
    <p>SimpleX Chat features:</p>
    <ol>
      <li>end-to-end encrypted messages, with editing, replies and deletion of messages.</li>
      <li>sending end-to-end encrypted images and files.</li>
      <li>single-use and long-term user addresses.</li>
      <li>secret chat groups - only group members know it exists and who is the member.</li>
      <li>end-to-end encrypted audio and video calls.</li>
      <li>private instant notifications.</li>
      <li>portable chat profile - you can transfer your chat contacts and history to another device (terminal or mobile).</li>
    </ol>
    <p>SimpleX Chat advantages:</p>
    <ol>
      <li><em>Full privacy of your identity, profile, contacts and metadata:</em> unlike any other existing messaging platform, SimpleX uses no phone numbers or any other identifiers assigned to the users - not even random numbers. This protects the privacy of who you are communicating with, hiding it from SimpleX platform servers and from any observers.</li>
      <li><em>Complete protection against spam and abuse:</em> as you have no identifier on SimpleX platform, you cannot be contacted unless you share a one-time invitation link or an optional temporary user address.</li>
      <li><em>Full ownership, control and security of your data:</em> SimpleX stores all user data on client devices, the messages are only held temporarily on SimpleX relay servers until they are received.</li>
      <li><em>Decentralized network:</em> you can use SimpleX with your own servers and still communicate with people using the servers that are pre-configured in the apps or any other SimpleX servers.</li>
    </ol>
    <p>You can connect to anybody you know via link or scan QR code (in the video call or in person) and start sending messages instantly - no emails, phone numbers or passwords needed.</p>
    <p>Your profile and contacts are only stored in the app on your device - our servers do not have access to this information.</p>
    <p>All messages are end-to-end encrypted using open-source double-ratchet protocol; the messages are routed via our servers using open-source SimpleX Messaging Protocol.</p>
  </description>

  <releases>
    <release version="5.8.1" date="2024-06-19">
      <description>
        <p>General:</p>
        <ol>
          <li>fixes in sending/receiving files.</li>
          <li>better error reporting when connecting to desktop app.</li>
          <li>prevent forwarding to conversations where conversation preferences do not allow message.</li>
        </ol>
        <p>Android and desktop apps:</p>
        <ol>
          <li>support transparent theme colors for chat message bubbles.</li>
          <li>do not reset changed network settings when switching SOCKS proxy on/off</li>
          <li>fix swipe to reply when animation is disabled.</li>
          <li>fix bug when duplicate group shown in the UI.</li>
        </ol>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  
  <url type="homepage">https://simplex.chat/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/simplex-chat/simplex-chat/issues</url>
  <url type="donation">https://opencollective.com/simplex-chat</url>
  <url type="translate">https://simplex.chat/docs/translations</url>
  <url type="faq">https://simplex.chat/faq</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/simplex-chat/simplex-chat</url>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">chat.simplex.simplex.desktop</launchable>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#a5f0ff</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#110e26</color>
  </branding>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://simplex.chat/blog/images/simplex-desktop-light.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
